# **Amr Mohamed**

iOS Software Engineer

♠ C	airo, Eg	ypt			
<u> + :</u>	2010046	7670	<u>)1</u>		
≥< iA	mrMoha	med	@gmail.	com	<u>l</u>
₩ Pc	ortfolio		Github	in	Linkedin

# Summary

iOS Software Engineer with nearly 5 years experience in crafting the best user experience, I am constantly passionate about learning new technologies and always looking forward to make my self better. I keep reading books every day about iOS Development and software engineering, I learned most of my experience from reading <a href="raywenderlich">raywenderlich</a> books and also from reading <a href="Apple programming guides">Apple programming guides</a> while I was student my graduation project was a video editing iOS app that is all about capturing editing, exporting and playing slow motion videos using <a href="APFoundation">APFoundation</a> framework.

## Education

University of Sinai, El-Arish, North Sinai,

B.S in Information Technology, 2012 - 2016.

## Experience

## iOS Software Engineer at MO4 Network

May 2018 - Present

• Currently working on a secret project that hasn't come out yet, but it's all about realtime messages, chatting, artificial intelligence and machine learning.

## iOS Software Engineer at Spectra

Mar 2017 - Apr 2018

- <u>Spare</u> is a social platform that allows people to sell their own car replacement parts and accessories in 6 different countries in middle east.
- <u>Taahel</u> is a mobile app that helps people with special needs to find hospitals, schools and medical supplies for people with special needs, and also allows patient to find doctors, partners, drivers near their current location.

#### iOS Software Engineer at EraMint

Jan 2015 - Feb 2017

- <u>Johnson</u> is a mobile app that allows KSA car owners to try out the tinting of the back and rear glass of their cars in a real world 3D Model .
- <u>Elogra</u> is a mobile app to help passengers to calculate fares and change for each chair in the 4 different type of car transportation in Egypt .
- <u>E-Toggar</u> is a social platform that links the product to the final consumer without the need for intermediaries in the veterinary, agricultural field.

- <u>Kreaz</u> is a mobile app for selling Kreaz delicious eastern and western pastries, you can also design your own tarts with your own images from the gallery, and you can put any text on the tart and move it around with images.
- Ewsally is a mobile app that uses your current location to offer you awesome local deals on everything near you from restaurants, cafes, hyper markets, electronics, computers, clothing shops and more.

#### Independent & Contract iOS Developer

Jun 2013 - Present

- <u>Mal3abk</u> is a social media that aims at gathering trainers, players and playgrounds for sports like soccer, tennis, basket ball and others in Saudi Arabia .
- Ekeif is a social media that produces short and high quality videos in Arabic language, targeting Arabic speaker viewers worldwide, videos aims to answer the most important question, "How?" in six different categories .
- <u>Almasar</u> is a mobile app of the RTA official monthly Magazine it includes a number of topics and news related to the projects and various Agencies of the RTA .
- <u>SlooMo</u> is a social media app made for sharing videos from smart phones, it captures, edits, exports videos into slow motion videos .
- Qurany is one of the largest Holy Quran apps on the App Store, you can download all Quran Surahs from up to 70 reciters and 10 different printed versions of the Quran .

## **Open Sources**

- <u>AMVideoRangeSlider</u> is an iOS open source video range slider written in Swift, it can be used in a video editing apps to allow trimming videos in a visually appealing way, it was mainly developed for the <u>SlooMo</u> iOS app.
- <u>AMSIoMoRangeSlider</u> is an iOS open source slow motion video range slider written in Swift it can be used in slow motion video editing apps, it was mainly developed for the <u>SlooMo</u> iOS app mimicking the default iOS slow motion range slider.

#### Skills

- Swift (4 Years),
- Objective-C (2 Year),
- C++ (1 Year),
- UIKit (5 Years),
- WatchKit (1 Years),
- MapKit, CoreLocation,
- CoreGraphics, CoreAnimation,
- Photos, CoreImage, AVFoundation,

- ARKit, CoreML, CoreMotion,
- CoreData, Realm, SQLite, Firebase,
- Unit & UI Testing,
- Source Control & Git,
- Software Engineering,
- Agile Scrum Methodologies,
- Dependency Management Tools.